

## **Bogdan Vlad**

# **Summary**

A determined and enthusiastic professional, graduated in Marketing
Specialist, with +2 years experience in Management and a current student
at Code Institute. Skilled on Front-End and Back-End development,
currently working on a project with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, Python.
Looking to secure a role in Front-End or Back-End to develop my personal
skills within coding industry.

## **Experience**

### 2018-07 -2018-10

#### Invade International

Junior Web Developer

- working closely with the senior developer to gain new development insights
- developing using JavaScript and C# in WebStorm and Visual Studio tasks given by the senior developer
- designing the Front-End of the application that is used by call-centers all around the world using HTML, CSS, TypeScript and Node.JS
- getting trained and working with CentOS 7
- understanding and learning about Asterisk, CATI servers and Voip technologies
- keeping the senior developer updated with my progress

### 2017-09 -2018-10

### **Code Institute - The Learning People**

Junior Web Developer

- Front End Development
- HTML, CSS, GitHub, UX Design, JavaScript, jQuery, Angular JS, Balsamiq, Bootstrap
- Back End Development
- Python, MySQL, API's, Mango DB, Flask, Data Visualisation, Heroku, Database Fundamentals
- Full Stack Development
- Django, Stripe payments, Paypal payments, GitHub Apps, Forums, Django's testing framework, Django's REST framework

### 2016-03 -2018-07

### **London Camera Exchange**

Senior Sales Assistant

- Sony products' sale growth by 60% which led to being sent for a professional training by Sony Company in November 2016
- being Top Salesman by meeting personal targets of £20k which resulted in growth of conversion by 50%
- demonstrating desired behaviours for staff including driving sales, which lead to growth of sales by 30% within the company
- being responsible for studio photography, photography lessons, marketing via social media
- answering queries from customers, being responsible for processing cash and card payments, dealing with customers refunds/complains



#### Phone

07951492121

#### E-mail

bogdan.vlad.v@gmail.com



### Languages

English

Full professional proficiency

French

Basic working proficiency

Romanian

••••• Native



**Time Management** 

Customer service

••••

**Problem Solving Abilities** 

••••

Creativity

HTML/CSS

TypeScript, NodeJS

jQuery

JavaScript/Libraries

Bootstrap

GitHub

Adobe Photoshop

2016-01 -2016-03

### **JD Sports Bristol Airport**

Assistant Store Manager

- developing personal skills via Manager Assessment Program
- receiving an award for the Best Retailer Store in 2016 at Bristol Airport
- accomplishing Tax Free policy by the airport which leads to growth of sales by 50%
- demonstrating desired behaviours for staff including driving sales, which lead to growth of sales of Top 25 line products by 30% in area
- managing deliveries with 97% accuracy which resulted in 3% losses due to the manufacturer oddments within last 8 months
- drawing weekly figure reports of 3 best performing stores to the Area Manager
- helping Area Manager in identifying training needs and providing ongoing training opportunities to the team as needed

2015-06 -2016-01

### **JD Sports Bristol Airport**

Store Supervisor

- ensuring company standards are being met for the store and associate appearance at all times, which resulted in being marked for 90% out of 100% in a report by Mystery Shopper for Customer Service
- setting individual staff targets, monitoring and providing feedback which resulted in growth of area top 25 lines by 20% in comparison to last year branch trade review
- managing paperwork on daily basis, cash floats and keeping the variation under the allowance, resulted in being marked for 95% in a Loss Control report
- improving store conversion by acknowledging area of decline, which leads to improvement of footfall of textiles department by 15% due to weekly wall sales comparison and changes of layout
- keeping up to date training opportunities regarding company policy via
   Intranet platform which are essential for store overall results in a Loss
   Control report

2014-11 -2015-06

### JD Sports, Bristol

Sales Assistant

- assisting shoppers to find the goods and products they are looking for, giving guidance on product selection to customers
- responsible dealing with customer complaints and reporting discrepancies to the supervisor
- working within established guidelines, particularly with brands
- being responsible for security within the store and being on the look out for the shoplifters and fraudulent credit cards
- keeping up to date with special promotions and putting out displays

2011-09 -2014-11

### F64 Studio, Bucharest

Senior Sales Advisor

- achieving targets and deadlines which lead to growth of sales of 10% reported by Store Manager • selling photo/video equipment and accessories, mobile phones and tablets
- testing new and unfamiliar products to deliver a complete picture to the customers demand
- keeping up to date with all of the products, services and promotions at all times

- being aware of competitive intelligence and marketing intelligence
- engaging customers in genuine and enjoyable conversations to understand their needs

## **Education**

present

Nicolae Titulescu University, Bucharest
 2014-07
 BA Marketing Specialist
 Edinburgh Napier University

2008-09 - Cefora Business School, Bucharest
2010-06 European Diploma in Sales

Full Stack Web Developer

## **Q** Certificates

JavaScript & jQuery Tutorial CourseHTML & CSS Fundamentals Course

2017-06 • Google-Mobile Site Developer

2017-02 • Google Analytics, Google AdWords

2013-05 • Photography Certificate (F64 Studio)